A Guide to the Papers of C. Brian Kelly, 1963-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of C. Brian Kelly 1963-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10566-b
This collection consists of ca. 750 items, 6 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by C. Brian Kelly, University of Virginia, on August 16, 2002
Biographical/Historical Information
C. Brian Kelly, of Charlottesville, Virginia, is a former journalist, magazine editor, columnist for Military History magazine, and University of Virginia English professor.
Scope and Content
These files contain research items, drafts, notes and copies of articles and books written by C. Brian Kelly. The majority of the material concerns Allied Chemical and the presence of Kepone in the James River. Also included in the files are drafts and page proofs of two books upon which he collaborated with his wife, Ingrid Smyer: The Best Little Stories from the Civil War and The Best Little Ironies, Oddities and Mysteries of the Civil War. Most of the material in the collection is dated between 1960 and 2000, with some research material dating back to 1928.
Contents List
- AFL-CIO Bulletins and Job Safety 1969-1975 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Best Little Ironies, Oddities and Mysteries of the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Early Typescript (1 of 2 folders) c. 1999 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Best Little Ironies, Oddities and Mysteries of the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Early Typescript (2 of 2 folders) c. 1999 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Best Little Ironies, Oddities and Mysteries of the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly Including "Mary Todd Lincoln: Troubled First Lady" by Ingrid Smyer- Typescript (1 of 3 folders) 2000 April (Box-folder 1:4)
- Best Little Ironies, Oddities and Mysteries of the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly Including "Mary Todd Lincoln: Troubled First Lady" by Ingrid Smyer- Typescript (2 of 3 folders) 2000 April (Box-folder 1:5)
- Best Little Ironies, Oddities and Mysteries of the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly Including "Mary Todd Lincoln: Troubled First Lady" by Ingrid Smyer- Typescript (3 of 3 folders) 2000 April (Box-folder 1:6)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Description of Typesetting and Page Design Process by Lani Aikin Boaz 1994 September (Box-folder 1:7)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Early Corrected Page Proofs (1 of 3 folders) 1994 September (Box-folder 1:8)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Early Corrected Page Proofs (2 of 3 folders) 1994 September (Box-folder 1:9)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Early Corrected Page Proofs (3 of 3 folders) 1994 September (Box-folder 1:10)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Page Proofs (1 of 3 folders) 1994 October (Box-folder 1:11)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Page Proofs (2 of 3 folders) 1994 October (Box-folder 2:1)
- Best Little Stories from the Civil War by C. Brian Kelly - Page Proofs (3 of 3 folders) 1994 October (Box-folder 2:2)
- Best Little Stories Series - Book covers and Advertisement n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Book Jacket for Tales of the Clubhouse Cat by C.B. Kay (C. Brian Kelly) n.d. (Oversize Oversize)
- Cigarette Bootlegging - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations 1976 November-December (Box-folder 2:4)
- "Cigarette Bootlegging: A State and Federal Responsibility?" Manuscript Fragment n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Colonization 1928, 1962 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Commonwealth of Virginia House of Delegates - Issues and Proceedings 1976 (Box-folder 2:7)
- Environment and Pollution 1976-1979 (Box-folder 2:8)
- Joint Chiefs of Staff Special Historical Study 1988 (Box-folder 2:9)
- John F. Kennedy - Re-opening Assassination Investigation 1975 April-May (Box-folder 2:10)
  Includes notes by Kelly about screenings of the Zapruder film in April and May arranged by University of Virginia students Andy Purdy and Mike Holm; mentions congressmen Robert Daniel, Tom Downing, Henry Gonzalez and Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr.
- Kepone - Allied Chemical 1963-1979 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Kepone - Allied Chemical - Annual Reports 1975-1978 (Box-folder 2:12)
- Kepone - Article Drafts (1 of 3 folders) 1975-1978 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Kepone - Article Drafts (2 of 3 folders) 1975-1978 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Kepone - Article Drafts (3 of 3 folders) 1975-1978 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Kepone - Bass Anglers' Sportsman Society 1976 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Kepone - Civil Action - William P. Moore v. Allied Chemical n.d. (Box-folder 3:5)
- Kepone - Correspondence 1975-1980 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Kepone - Department of Health, Education and Welfare 1976-1978, n.d (Box-folder 3:7)
- Kepone - Environmental Protection Agency (1 of 2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Kepone - Environmental Protection Agency (2 of 2 folders) 1977-1978, n.d (Box-folder 3:9)
- Kepone - Environmental Protection Agency - Hearings 1977 June 26 (Box-folder 3:10)
- Kepone - Environmental Protection Agency - Mathematical Evaluation of Kepone Action Levels 1977 January (Box-folder 3:11)
- Kepone - Food and Drug Administration 1977 (Box-folder 3:12)
- Kepone - Governor Mills E. Goodwin, et. al. 1976-1978 (Box-folder 3:13)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Beginning Draft n.d. (Box-folder 3:14)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Draft (1 of 2 folders) 1979 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Draft (2 of 2 folders) 1979 (Box-folder 4:2)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Draft - Nadar Typescript Footnotes - Kelly Biographical Information 1979 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Drafts and Notes 1979 (Box-folder 4:4)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Edits and Inserts 1980 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Kepone - Kepone Chapter - Final 1980 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Kepone - Kepone Intoxication in Man - Department of Neurology, Medical College of Virginia. 1976 (Box-folder 4:7)
- Kepone - National Pest Control Association 1976 October (Box-folder 4:8)
- Kepone - Newsclippings (1 of 5 folders) 1975 (Box-folder 4:9)
- Kepone - Newsclippings (2 of 5 folders) 1976 January-April (Box-folder 4:10)
- Kepone - Newsclippings (3 of 5 folders) 1976 May-July (Box-folder 4:11)
- Kepone - Newsclippings (4 of 5 folders) 1976 August-December (Box-folder 4:12)
- Kepone - Newsclippings (5 of 5 folders) 1977-1980, n.d. (Box-folder 4:13)
- Kepone - Notes c.1976 (Box-folder 4:14)
- Kepone - Pennsylvania Department of Environmental Resources 1977-1978 (Box-folder 4:15)
- Kepone - Pictures n.d. (Box-folder 4:16)
- Kepone - Rachel Carson Trust 1975-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 5:1)
- Kepone - Reports and Research Materials 1976-1978, n.d. (Box-folder 5:2)
- Kepone - Research - "The Science of Total Environment" 1978 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Kepone - "Review of Studies on the Toxicity and Carcinogenity of Kepone" n.d. (Box-folder 5:4)
- Kepone - Toxic Substance Control Act 1975-1976 (Box-folder 5:5)
- Kepone - "Toxicological, Pathological and Statistical Considerations Relating to the Kepone Action Levels" n.d. (Box-folder 5:6)
- Kepone - Virginia Department of Agriculture and Commerce 1977 (Box-folder 5:7)
- Kepone - Virginia Department of Health 1976-1977 (Box-folder 5:8)
- Kepone - Virginia Environmental Endowment 1977-1979 (Box-folder 5:9)
- Kepone - Virginia Institute of Marine Science 1976-1979 (Box-folder 5:10)
- Kepone - Virginia State Water Control Board 1976 (Box-folder 5:11)
- Kepone - Virginia Polytechnic Institute - College of Agriculture and Life Sciences 1977 (Box-folder 5:12)
- Kepone - Waste Disposal - United States and Maryland 1976 (Box-folder 5:13)
- Latin America 1959-1962, n.d. (Box-folder 5:14)
- Law Enforcement and Prison Systems 1975 (Box-folder 5:15)
- Miscellaneous News 1975-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 5:16)
- News clippings - The IUE News 1972-1975 (Box-folder 5:17)
- Peace Corps 1961-1963 (Box-folder 6:1)
- Politics and Political Issues 1977 (Box-folder 6:2)
- Sugar Grove Radio Telescope 1960-1961 (Box-folder 6:3)
- Urban Assistance Incentive Fund 1977 (Box-folder 6:4)
- University of Virginia - News Releases 1977 (Box-folder 6:5)